Adnan Shaikh

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

University of Mumbai -Maharashtra | 06/2015

Graduated EXTC Engineering with an Average of 67%

SKILLS

Java Hibernate

Oracle Microservices

Spring Kafka

Git JUnit

React Redis

CONTACT



8655868744



adnanshaikh53@gmail.com



Mumbai, Maharashtra



adnanshaikh53.github.io

PROFILE

I am a Software Developer with around 7 years of Experience in Software Development specialized in Java, from Mumbai who loves to write Software to build great Products and help businesses succeed with their goals.

I have been working professionally in Software Development since 2015 across the Web space with experience in Payments and Security domain.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Qualys, Inc - Mumbai, Maharashtra I 07/2021 - Present

- Developed External Attack Surface management Product for Qualys from scratch.
- Solely Responsible for API Gateway and Job Scheduling for a large client base.
- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues.
- Trained and mentored junior developers and engineers, performed code-reviews and gave appropriate feedback.

Senior Software Engineer

Finastra - Mumbai, Maharashtra I 02/2018 - 07/2021

- Worked on High Value Mass Pay Enhancements for Global Payplus in Finastra.
- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues.
- Managed Customer defects for Citibank, Citibanamex, Statestreet Bank and provided technical support for the same.

Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) - Mumbai, Maharashtra I 09/2015 - 02/2018

- Created iON Lite a minified free version of the parent iON ERP Product.
- Worked in TCS iON as a Java developer in ERP/ Manufacturing domain
- Responsible for Bill Of Material and Job Order modules.